这里是重庆市二零二二年初中学业水平暨高中招生考试
英语听力测试部分，请考生们做好
听音和答题准备。
第一节，听一遍。
根据你所听到的句子，从
三个选项中选出最恰当的答语，并把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
每小题，你将有八秒钟的时间读题和答题。
1. Good morning, boys and girls.
2. Would you like some tea?
3. Mom, I can play this piece of music well.
4. Happy birthday, Mark.
5. I will take a trip to
6. Please be careful when you climb the mountain.
第二节：听一遍。
根据你所听到的对话和问题，从
三个选项中选出正确答案，并把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
每小题，你将有八秒钟的时间读题和答题。
7. Wow, is that Peter?
He looks different now.
Yes, he used to be thin and short.
Question, who used to be thin and short?
8. How do you usually go to school, Linda?
I take the bus every day.
Question, how does Linda usually go to school?
9. I think computers and trains are great inventions.
I agree with you.
Question, what are they talking about?
10. Jenny, which season do you like better, spring or summer?
Spring. Question, which season does Jenny like better?
11. When did you start to learn physics, Mike?
Two years ago.
Question, how long has Mike learned physics?
12. Why do you study in the library,
Because it's quiet.
Question, why does Gina study in the library?
第三节。
听两遍。
根据你所听到的长对话，从
the A, B, question.
三个选项中选出正确答案，并把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
听长对话前，你将有。
十秒钟的时间阅读各个小题，
听完后你将有十秒钟的时间答题。
听第一段材料，回答第十三和十四小题。
cost for two tickets is $5.
Okay. Do you sell all -day passes?
Yes, $5 each.
I'd like two all -day passes.
Here is $10.
Thank you. Have a nice day.
Thank you, too.
Line 6 will take you there.
The cost for two tickets is $5.
Okay. Do you sell all -day passes?
Yes, $5 each.
I'd like two all -day passes.
Here is $10.
Thank you. Have a nice day.
Thank you, too.
听第二段材料，回答第十五和十六小题。
What's matter? I didn't wear enough clothes, so I've got a cold.
Oh, you'd better drink some hot water.
Thank you. You're welcome.
By the way, will you visit the village school again?
Sure. We plan to visit it again next month.
Good. I will go with you.
We brought some books to the village school and we played games with the students.
Sounds good. Oh, you don't look well.
What's the matter?
I didn't wear enough clothes, so I've got a cold.
Oh, you'd better drink some hot water.
Thank you. You're welcome.
By the way, will you visit the village school again?
Sure. We plan to visit it again next month.
Good. I will go with you.
第四节，听两遍。
根据你所听到的短文内容，从
三个选项中选出正确答案，并把答题卡上对应题目的答案标号涂黑。
听短文前，你将有二十秒钟的时间
阅读各个小题。
听完后，你将有二十秒钟的时间答题。
with you. Thank you for calling Jane's Sports Center.
Sorry that we are closed this weekend because of the heavy rain and storm.
And here is some useful information for you.
If you like playing ball games, then Jane's Sports Center has something for you.
We have the best coaches from all over China and they can teach you to play any ball
game. We also have the best football team for girls and our coach is from Liaoning.
We offer one of the playgrounds for free on Saturday afternoon.
It's free only when you come with your parent.
But one thing is that you should wear sports clothes and shoes.
For more information, please call Anna at 65509823.
Don't stop exercising at home or in your school.
Hope the weather will be fine.
See you soon.
Thank you for calling Jane's Sports Center.
Sorry that we are closed this weekend because of the heavy rain and storm.
And here is some useful information for you.
If you like playing ball games, then Jane's Sports Center has something for you.
We have the best coaches from all over China and they can teach you to play any ball
game. We also have the best football team for girls and our coach is from Liaoning.
We offer one of the playgrounds for free on Saturday afternoon.
It's free only when you come with your parent.
But one thing is that you should wear sports clothes and shoes.
For more information, please call Anna at 65509823.
Don't stop exercising at home or in your school.
Hope the weather will be fine.
See you soon.
听力测试完毕，请考。
学生们继续完成其他试题
Thank you